thehealthsite.com 2015-12-08

# PRIVACY POLICY

[Home](http://www.thehealthsite.com/) / PRIVACY POLICY

**PRIVACY POLICY OF INDIA.COM**

The terms and conditions contained in this policy constitutes the privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) governing the use of the Web Site (as defined in the Terms of Use) and shall be construed as a part of the Terms of Use. This Privacy Policy is designed to answer your questions regarding our privacy policies and principles.

The company, India Webportal Pvt Ltd and its affiliates respect your privacy. This privacy policy describes the treatment of information, provided or collected, on the sites where this privacy policy is posted. It also explains the treatment of information provided or collected on applications we make available on third-party sites or platforms if disclosed to you in connection with use of the application.

We follow this privacy policy in accordance with local laws prevailing in the places where we operate. This Policy does not apply to the procedures and practices followed by entities that are not managed, owned or controlled by the Company and the site/service india.com or to the people that are not engaged, employed or managed by the Company the site/service india.com.

A. GENERAL  
B. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY US  
C. HOW WE USE AND SHARE THE INFORMATION  
D. CHOICES YOU HAVE ABOUT THE COLLECTION, USE, AND SHARING OF YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION  
E. CORRECTION OF INFORMATION  
F. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

A. GENERAL:

Thank you for visiting http://www.thehealthsite.com by continued access to this site you give your implied consent to the terms and conditions mentioned hereunder, in case of refusal, we request you to leave the site. This Privacy Policy applies only to personally identifiable information collected on the Web sites where this Privacy Policy is posted and does not apply to any other information collected by India Webportal Pvt. Ltd., through any other means. This Privacy Policy applies to use and sharing of personally identifiable information collected before, on, and after the date that this Privacy Policy is posted. We will also apply this Privacy Policy to personally identifiable information collected in the course of Non-Registered Transactions (as defined below) that occurred prior to the date that this Privacy Policy is posted, but only if the guest accepts the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy.

TheHealthSite.com (the “Web Site”) is controlled and run by India Webportal Pvt. Ltd. As used in this Privacy Policy, India Webportal Pvt. includes India.com and all of its subsidiaries and affiliated entities, portals, websites, as well as companies that generally offer their products and services under the “india.com ” brand name, and are referred to in this Privacy Policy as “we,” “us,” “our,” and “ourselves.”

In keeping with the traditions of India Webportal Pvt. Ltd, we refer to customers of India Webportal Pvt. Ltd as “guests.” When this Privacy Policy uses the term “personally identifiable information,” we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as the individual’s name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card details, bank account details, gender and age. When other information, such as consumer product preferences or number of children, is directly associated with personally identifiable information, this other information also becomes personally identifiable information for purposes of this Privacy Policy. Personally identifiable information is sometimes referred to in this Privacy Policy as “personal information.” Finally, the terms of this Privacy Policy are subject to all applicable laws.

B. INFORMATION COLLECTED BY US:

1\. Information You Provide to Us

Much of the personally identifiable information we receive comes directly from guests who are interested in obtaining various products and services from us. Typically, this information includes the guest’s name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information, and information about your interests in and use of various products, programs, and services, In the course of these various offerings. We may also collect other types of information such as gender, age, number of children, and personal interests, which we may associate with personally identifiable information. If you purchase products or services from us, we will note, for example, credit card information, the type of services or products ordered or purchased, and the date of the order or purchase. We collect personal information when you register on, log on, or visit our Web sites, including when you participate in activities on our Web sites, such as sweepstakes, contests, games and promotional offers.

At some stage in this site, you may also submit information about other people. For example, you might submit a person’s name and e-mail address to share an article / story OR you might submit the recipient’s name and address, if you are sending a product /gift directly to that person.

At certain parts of some of our sites, only persons who provide us with the requested personally identifiable information will be able to avail of special offers, to order products, programs, and services or otherwise participate in the site’s activities and offerings. The Information so provided shall be completely voluntary.

We make chat rooms, forums, instant messenger and message boards and other services available to you. Please understand that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. We have no control over its use and you should exercise caution when disclosing your personal information to anyone.

If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

We are the sole owners of your information collected by us at several different points on our Website.

2\. Information Collected Through Technology

We collect information through technology to make our sites more interesting and useful to you. For instance, when you come to one of our sites we collect your IP address. An IP address is often associated with the portal through which you enter the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone your IP address is not personally identifiable. We also may use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information.

Our Web sites also use cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site sends to your computer while you are viewing the Web site. We and other companies use cookies for a variety of purposes. For instance, when you return to one of our sites after logging in, cookies provide information to the site so that the site will remember who you are. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won’t have access to many features that make your Web experience smoother (like the features mentioned above) and some of our services will not function properly.

Our Web sites use a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including Web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of Web sites. We also use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on our Web sites, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of our Web sites. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML e-mails that we send our guests to determine whether our guests have opened those e-mails and/or clicked on links in those e-mails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable.

Many advertisements are managed and placed on our Web sites by third parties. These companies are called “network advertisers.” Network advertisers who place advertisements on our Web sites may also use cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information when you click on or move your cursor over one of their banner advertisements. You may not realize this information is being collected. In some cases, we may have access to information from Web beacons and cookies used by network advertisers on our sites and this information may permit us to identify other sites that you have visited that are also associated with the network advertiser. Finally, once you’ve clicked on an advertisement and have left our Web sites, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser to see how your personal information will be handled on their site.

We, our service providers, advertisers and affiliates may collect various types of non-personally identifiable information when you visit any of our sites. A list representing the types of non-personally identifiable information we may collect include: current Internet protocol address and type of browser you are using , the type of operating system you are using, the domain name of your Internet service provider , the web pages you have visited, sites visited before and after you visit our site, the type of handheld or mobile device used to view the site, location information, the content you have accessed and the advertisements you have been shown and/or clicked on.

When you provide information through social media account, it can help enable us to do things like (1) give you exclusive content, (2) personalize your online experience with us within and outside our applications or websites, and (3) contact you through the social networking sites or directly by sending you the latest news, special offerings, and rewards. By doing so, you consent to the use of this information in accordance with our privacy policy. When you provide personal information to us through an application, on our sites, or on social networking sites, it may be publicly viewed by other members of these sites and we cannot prevent further use of the information by third parties.

Through some social networking sites’ privacy settings, you can control what data you share. For more information about how social networking sites handle your personal information, please refer to their privacy policies and terms of use.

3\. Information That We Collect from Others

We may supplement personally identifiable information that we have collected directly from our guests with other information that we obtain from third parties and other members / affiliates of India Webportal Pvt. Ltd.

In addition, we may obtain information about individuals who are not yet users of our Web sites or guests of India Webportal Pvt. Ltd. In addition, when we associate information that we obtain from third parties or other members / affiliates of India Webportal Pvt. Ltd with personally identifiable information that we have collected under this Privacy Policy, we will treat the acquired information like the information that we collected ourselves and, except as permitted by this Privacy Policy, the information will not be shared with third parties.

C. HOW WE USE AND SHARE THE INFORMATION

India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may use your personally identifiable information in many ways, including sending you promotional materials, and sharing your information with third parties so that these third parties can send you promotional materials. (By “promotional materials,” we mean communications that directly promote the use of our Web sites, or the purchase of products or services.)

1\. India Webportal Pvt, Licensees and Co-Branding Participants

Personally identifiable information collected under this Privacy Policy is shared among and used by India Webportal Pvt Ltd. for many purposes. For example, India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may use your personal information to send you promotional materials about goods and services (including special offers and promotions) either offered by India Webportal Pvt Ltd. or offered by third parties. These promotional materials may be sent to you by postal mail, e-mail or other means. Please keep in mind, however, that when you purchase or request products or services from India Webportal Pvt Ltd., promotional materials may accompany delivery of that product or service.

India Webportal Pvt. Ltd. may also use your personal information for many purposes other than sending you promotional materials. (We refer to all of these types of uses of your personal information that do not involve the sending of promotional materials as “Operational Uses.”)For example, we may use your information to complete transactions requested by you (such as your purchase of a product or service offered on our Web sites), or to send you administrative communications either about your account with us or about features of our Web sites, including any future changes to this Privacy Policy.

In addition to using your personal information within India Webportal Pvt Ltd., India Webportal Pvt. Ltd., may share your personal information with companies that offer products and/or services under brand names of India Webportal Pvt. Ltd. These companies are called “licensees.” For example, a company that publishes and sells books under the ” India Webportal Pvt Ltd.” brand would be such a licensee.

India Webportal Pvt. Ltd., may also share your information with companies that offer products and/or services that are co-branded using brand names of India Webportal Pvt Ltd.

When India Webportal Pvt Ltd. shares personal information with third parties acting as licensees and co-branding participants, these licensees and co-branding participants are restricted by contract from using the personal information for any marketing or promotional purpose that is not related to a licensed or co-branded product or service.

You may engage in transactions (such as purchasing products or services) without registering and logging on our Web sites. These transactions may be either with us or with other affiliated members of India Webportal Pvt Ltd. (We refer to all of these transactions that you engage in without registering and logging on our Web sites as “Non-Registered Transactions.”) An example would be when you purchase items through an India Webportal Pvt Ltd. e-commerce service without registering and logging on that Web site. When you engage in Non-Registered Transactions your information will not be shared with third parties and will not be used by any member of India Webportal Pvt Ltd. to send you promotional materials other than the member involved in your transaction, except as separately permitted by other provisions of this Privacy Policy.

Finally, India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may take your personally identifiable information and make it non-personally identifiable, either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you (de-personalizing your information). Given the nature of this information, there are no restrictions under this Privacy Policy upon the right of India Webportal Pvt Ltd. to aggregate or de-personalize your personal information, and India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may use and/or share with third parties the resulting non-personally identifiable information in any way.

2\. Third Parties Offering Promotions, Products, or Services

India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may share your personal information with selected third parties so that they can send you promotional materials about goods and services (including special offers and promotions) offered by them. When sharing your information for promotional purposes, India Webportal Pvt Ltd. attempts to select only reputable companies that offer high quality products and services.

Moreover, India Webportal Pvt Ltd. will not share your e-mail address with third parties for promotional purposes, except when you consent to such sharing in the course of your participation in a Sponsored Activity.

India Webportal Pvt Ltd may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties whose practices are not covered by this privacy statement (e.g., other marketers, magazine publishers, retailers, participatory databases, and non-profit organizations) that want to market products or services to you.

When India Webportal Pvt Ltd. shares your personal information with a third party under any circumstance described in this “Third Parties Offering Promotions, Products, or Services” section, your personal information will become permanently subject to the information use and sharing practices of the third party, and the third party will not be restricted by this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information.

In addition to the promotional sharing that is subject to your choices India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may also share your information when you engage in certain activities on our sites that are sponsored by third parties, such as purchasing products or services offered by a third party, electing to receive information or communications from a third party, or electing to participate in contests, sweepstakes, games or other programs sponsored in whole or in part by a third party.

India Webportal Pvt Ltd. may also share your personal information when you respond to promotional materials from India Webportal Pvt Ltd. and authorize a third party to use your personal information for purposes such as, for example, sending you additional promotional materials, providing you a product or service, or entering you in a contest, sweepstakes or game. (We refer to all of these activities and requests as “Sponsored Activities.”) When you participate in Sponsored Activities, you will either be required or requested to agree that the sponsor or business associate may use your personal information (including, in some cases, your e-mail address) in accordance with the sponsor or business associate’s privacy practices.

3\. Companies That Facilitate Communications and Transactions with You

Sometimes India Webportal Pvt Ltd. hires companies to help deliver products or services, like a shipping company that delivers a package or a company that helps fulfill prizes. In those instances, there is a need to share your information with these companies.

Sometimes India Webportal Pvt Ltd. also works with other companies who help either gather your information or communicate with you. Except as separately permitted by other provisions of this Privacy Policy, these companies are allowed to gather, receive, and use your information only for the purposes described in this paragraph or as required by law.

4\. Companies That You Previously Authorized to Obtain Your Information

In certain circumstances, your dealings with a third party may have authorized that third party to obtain your personal information from India Webportal Pvt Ltd. and to use that information in accordance with the third party’s own privacy practices and policies. For example, in using an online shopping service (such as the shopping services offered by Internet portals that refer the portal’s users to third-party merchants), you may have authorized that shopping service to obtain from the service’s participating third-party merchants (including India Webportal Pvt Ltd.) information about your purchases conducted through the shopping service.

India Webportal Pvt Ltd.will provide such companies only the information that you authorized (except as separately permitted under other provisions of this Privacy Policy). In the example given above, the shopping service would be provided only information concerning purchases you made from India Webportal Pvt Ltd. through that shopping service, and would not be provided any other information concerning you, unless any additional sharing of your personal information were separately permitted under another provision of this Privacy Policy.

5\. Purchase or Sale of Businesses

From time to time, we may purchase a business or sell one or more of our businesses and your personally identifiable information may be transferred as a part of the purchase or sale.

In the event that we purchase a business, the personally identifiable information received with that business would be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy if it is practicable and permissible to do so.

In the event that we sell a business, we will include provisions in the selling contract requiring the purchaser to treat your personally identifiable information in the same manner required by this Privacy Policy (including any amendments to this Privacy Policy).

In light of this protection, nothing in this paragraph will affect our right to transfer your information to a purchaser in these circumstances. The provisions of this paragraph will also apply in the event that one or more businesses of any other member of India Webportal Pvt Ltd. are sold and personal information subject to this Privacy Policy is transferred to a purchaser of those businesses.

6\. Disclosures Required By Law and Disclosures to Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Web Sites, India Webportal Pvt Ltd. and Others

India Webportal Pvt Ltd. will disclose personal information when it believes in good faith that such disclosures (a) are required by law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena, or (b) will help to: enforce our Terms of Use; enforce contest, sweepstakes, promotions, and/or game rules; protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you; and/or, protect the safety and security of our Web sites, India Webportal Pvt Ltd., and/or third parties, including the safety and security of property that belongs to India Webportal Pvt Ltd. or third parties.

We may disclose personally identifiable in response to a law enforcement agency’s request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our terms of use, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our sites and applicable laws or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements.

We may use the information you provide about yourself to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, to offer you other products, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you, to enforce the legal terms that govern your use of our sites, and/or for the purposes for which you provided the information.

We may sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when you have won one of our contests or when we make changes to our subscriber agreements, to fulfill a request by you for an online newsletter, or to contact you about your account with us.

The information we collect in connection with our online forums and communities is used to provide an interactive experience. We may use this information to facilitate participation in these online forums and communities and, from time to time, to offer you products, programs, or services.

If you choose to submit content for publication (e.g., a letter to our editors, comments sent to our television personalities, a posting to a blog or a discussion board, a video), we may publish your screen name and other information you have provided to us.

We may on occasion combine information we collect through our sites with information that we collect from other sources .We use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our sites, to deliver more relevant marketing messages and advertisements and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information to analyze usage of our sites, as well as to offer you products, programs, or services.

7\. OTHERS

Some of our sites contain links to or integrations with other sites such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc., whose information practices may be different than ours. Visitors should consult the other sites’ privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

We also use the services of reputable third parties to provide us with data collection, reporting, ad response measurement, and site analytics, as well as to assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may view, edit or set their own cookies. We, our third party service providers, advertisers and/or partners may also place web beacons for these third parties. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this privacy statement.

Although we take appropriate measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that personally identifiable information that we collect will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this privacy statement.

D. CHOICES YOU HAVE ABOUT THE COLLECTION, USE, AND SHARING OF YOUR PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

India Webportal Pvt. Ltd., provides guests with the opportunity of deciding whether to receive unsolicited communications from India Webportal Pvt. Ltd and share personal information. This applies to information sent to Third Parties for promotions, products, and/or services unrelated to a specific transaction and information shared with India Webportal Pvt. Ltd, licensees, co-branding participants, and others from time to time. You may make this decision when you first register on the Web Site and you may change your decision at any time by visiting the website and following the required instructions for change

This decision to receive communications or share information will not apply to information shared with companies that facilitate communications and transactions with you, information shared with companies that you previously authorized to obtain your information, information transferred as part of the purchase or sale of businesses, information used by the India Webportal Pvt. Ltd for Operational Uses or Non-Registered Transactions (as defined above), disclosures required by law, or disclosures to help protect the security and safety of our web sites.

E. CORRECTION OF INFORMATION

Access to personally identifiable information that is collected from our sites and that we maintain may be available to you. For example, if you created a password-protected account within our site, you can access that account to review the information you provided.

India Webportal Pvt. Ltd provides you the ability to exercise certain controls and choices regarding our collection, use and sharing of your information. In accordance with local law, your controls and choices may include: 

You may correct, update and delete your registration account  
You may change your choices for subscriptions, newsletters and alerts  
You may choose whether to receive from us offers and promotions for our products and services, or products and services that we think may be of interest to you  
You may choose whether we share your personal information with other companies so they can send you offers and promotions about their products and services  
You may choose whether to receive targeted advertising from many ad networks, data exchanges, marketing analytics and other service providers here  
You may request access to the personal information we hold about you and that we amend or delete it and we request third parties with whom we have shared the information do the same.

F. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

India Webportal Pvt. Ltd. may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail at the last e-mail address that you provided us, and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the Web sites covered by this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon the earlier of thirty (30) calendar days following our dispatch of an e-mail notice to you or thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on the Web sites covered by this Privacy Policy.

Please note that, at all times, you are responsible for updating your personal information to provide us your current e-mail address. In the event that the last e-mail address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any other reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the e-mail containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice. In any event, changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of personal information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your information, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your account with us.

How you use data from Google’s Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics.

**Terms and conditions for the forum** :

1\. Do not post abusive content

This community is meant to help you lead your life in a healthier manner. Posting content that is abusive, threatening, offensive, defamatory, false, etc. will not be tolerated and could result in the user being banned.

2\. We are not responsible for the originality of the content you post

We encourage our users to post only original content. If at all, a user posts content that is copyrighted or licensed then Thehealthsite.com doesn’t take any responsibility for it. The users themselves are responsible for the content they post and the consequences of it. In case, a post that is plagiarized from elsewhere is brought to our notice, then we will surely remove it from our forums.

3\. Do not reveal personal information

Personal information like your address, phone number, etc. should not be revealed at any cost on this forum. Thehealthsite.com will not be responsible for any damage caused if a user does it. Any info you share on forums or any of our other sections including Ask an Expert and the Comments on Article pages can be picked up by third-party search engines. Please refrain from putting up very personal information.

4\. Do not spam

Promoting products and services that are questionable is highly discouraged. Users doing it are likely to face a ban along with their post being deleted.

5\. We are not responsible for the quality of the advice

TheHealthSite.com is not responsible for the efficacy of any advice that you find on the forums. In case of an emergency, please consult a doctor.
